A Guide to the Historical Slide Tour of Fairfax City, Virginia, 1976
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Historical Slide Tour of Fairfax City, Virginia, 1976
Fairfax County Public Library
0.5 linear feet
The Historical Slide Tour of Fairfax City, Virginia consists of 44 color photographic slides dating from 1976. They depict various buildings, structures, and other historic sites in Fairfax City, Virginia.
Junior Woman’s Club of Fairfax County
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Historical and Biographical Information
Between 1976-1977, the Arts Department of the Junior Woman’s Club of Fairfax County produced a slideshow entitled Historical Slide Tour of Fairfax City with the purpose of educating the public about local history. This slide tour was originally developed by the PTA at Green Acres School in Fairfax City, Virginia. Mr. Davis Hodge and Boy Scout Troop 882 allowed the school’s PTA to reproduce slides from Scout Martin E. Farmer’s The Fairfax City Historical Trail. Claudia Rucker wrote a script to accompany the presentation. The Junior Woman’s Club edited the PTA’s slide tour and produced six sets making them available to schools and other interested community organizations.
Scope and Content
The Historical Slide Tour of Fairfax City, Virginia consists of 44 color photographic slides dating from 1976. They depict various buildings, structures, and other historic sites in Fairfax City, Virginia. The slideshow was produced by the 1976-1977 Arts Department of the Junior Woman’s Club of Fairfax County.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax (Va.); Fairfax (Va.) -- History.; Fairfax (Va.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.
Container List
- c. 1976 (Box HST-001, Folder City Seal - Intro.)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-002, Folder George Mason's President's House - Roberts Road)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-003, Folder Aspen Grove)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-004, Folder Aspen Grove - Mr. Bob Becker)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-005, Folder Wake Robin)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-006, Folder The Carriage House)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-007, Folder Five Chimneys)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-008, Folder Five Chimneys - Close-up)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-009, Folder Five Chimneys - Chimney)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-010, Folder Blenheim)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-011, Folder Blenheim)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-012, Folder Blenheim - Attic Walls)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-013, Folder Blenheim - Attic Walls)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-014, Folder Library)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-015, Folder Post Office)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-016, Folder McCandlish House)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-017, Folder Ford Building)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-018, Folder Fairfax County Courthouse)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-019, Folder One-half of Truro Rectory)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-020, Folder Fairfax County Courthouse - Interior)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-021, Folder Martha Washington's Will)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-022, Folder Marr Monument)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-023, Folder Oliver House)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-024, Folder Barbour House)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-025, Folder Legato School)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-026, Folder City Hall)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-027, Folder Confederate Monument)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-028, Folder Truro Church)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-029, Folder Truro Rectory)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-030, Folder Mosby capturing Stoughton)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-031, Folder Mosby Marker)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-032, Folder Main Street, Fairfax City (circa 1903))
- c. 1976 (Box HST-033, Folder Main Street, Fairfax City (1975))
- c. 1976 (Box HST-034, Folder Fairfax Hay and Grain)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-035, Folder Fairfax Herald Building)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-036, Folder Old Printing Press)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-037, Folder Old Town Hall)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-038, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Exterior)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-039, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Hallway)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-040, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Sitting Room)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-041, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Main Room)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-042, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Stairway)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-043, Folder Earp's Ordinary - Bedroom)
- c. 1976 (Box HST-044, Folder Draper House)